Guide to the Collection of musical autographs,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Collection of Musical Autographs,
1870-1943
Seidl, Anton, 1850-1898.
48 boxes
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library. 535 West 114th St., New York, NY, 10027.
4079322
Biographical Note
Anton Seidl was a noted Wagnerian conductor and chorus master. He was born in Pest, Hungary, was a member of Wagner's household from 1872 to 1878, during which time he served as Wagner's musical secretary and later as conductor of the Richard Wagner Theater in Beyreuth. He was a close friend of Wagner's and had much to do with the spread of his music and influence through Europe and America.
Scope and Content
Papers, letters, memoranda, memorabilia, and manuscript music scores assembled by and related to the life and musical activities of Anton Seidl. The collection includes many letters from Cosima Wagner and her children addressed to Anton Seidl and Mrs. Seidl. There are also letters from Lilli Lehman, Edvard Grieg, Antonin Dvorak, Bronislaw Hubermann, Carl Goldmark, Maud Powell, Marianne Brandt, Felix Weingartner, Lyman Abbott, and many others. The letters are chiefly concerned with musical performances, composition, and related affairs. There are journals, diaries, and memoranda in Seidl's hand, as well as photographs and clippings relating to his conducting career. Also, twenty-seven manuscript scores of Seidl's orchestrations of various works.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 5 series:
Series I: Catalogued Correspondence
Series II: Cataloged Documents and Manuscripts
Series III: Clippings and Ephemera
Series IV: Photographs
Series V: Scores
Subjects
Wagner, Cosima, 1837-1930.; Lehman, Lilli.; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907.; Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904.; Huberman, Bronislaw.; Loewe, Carl, 1796-1869.; Mancinelli, Luigi, 1848-1921.; Mottl, Felix, 1856-1911.; Goldmark, Carl, 1830-1915.; Powell, Maud, 1867-1920.; Seidl-Kraus, Auguste, 1853-1939.; Brandt, Marianne.; Weingartner, Felix, 1863-1942.; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922.; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883.; Witmark, Isidore, 1871-1941.; Composers--Germany.; Composition (Music); Music--Germany--19th century.; Music--Performance--Germany.; Instrumentation and orchestration.; Musical scores.; Photoprints.; Articles.; Contracts.; Copyright certificates.; Diaries.; Essays.; Lists.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Photographs.; Scores.; Silhouettes.; Conductors (Music).; Musicians.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 7-48. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1905 M-05 Gift
06/21/1999 M-99-06-21 Wagner score insc. & signed by RW Schleicher, Ruth Gift
On deposit from the Music Library.
Gift of Ruth Schleicher, 1999.
- Series I: Catalogued Correspondence
  - Abbot, Lyman To Auguste Seidl, Brooklyn, NY, 9 April 1898, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    [With signed booklet "Love and Death" written by Abbott.9]
  - American National Institute To Anton Seidl, New York, 1896, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    [Acknowledgement of Seidl's donation of concert to benefit the Institute.]
  - Aus der Ohe, Adele To Mrs. Anton Seidl, Rome, Italy, 2 April 1898, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    [With postmarked envelope.]
  - Bauer, Harold To Walter Lawrence Bogart, New York, 10 June 1919, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bispham, David To Auguste Seidl, New York, 17 March 1899, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    [Regrets, unable to participate in Seidl memorial event.]
  - Brandt, Marianne To Auguste Seidl, New York, [n.d.], (2 pages a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    [Written on calling card.]
  - Bruckner, Anton [To Anton Seidl], [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 page a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    [On verso of calling card.]
  - Bruckner, Anton To Cecile Kohn Hollander, [Vienna], 17 November 1885, (2 pages a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    [On visiting card with envelope.]
  - Brull, Ignaz To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 10 January 1888, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brull, Ignaz To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 25 October 1888, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brull, Ignaz To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 22 January 1889, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - von Bulow, Blandine To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 3 July 1881, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - von Bulow, Blandine Gravina To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 26 July 1891, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - von Bulow, Daniela To "Grandfather" [Franz Liszt] in German with French translation in unknown hand, Bayreuth, 1878, (2 pages a.l.s., 1 page t.l., 2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    [Authenticity of original letter in question.]
  - von Bulow, Daniela To Anton Seidl, Beyreuth, 18 Sept 1883, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    [With postmarked envelope]
  - von Bulow, Daniela To Anton Seidl, Beyreuth, 7 March 1894, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - von Bulow, Daniela To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 20 May 1886, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - von Bulow, Daniela (Thode) To Anton Seidl, Bonn, 14 December 1887, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - von Bulow, Daniela (Thode) To Auguste Seidl, Gardone, Italy, 17 April 1898, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bungert, August To Anton Seidl, Pegli, Italy, [n.d.], (5 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bungert, August To Anton Seidl, Pegli, Italy, 8 May 1878, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bungert, August To Anton Seidl, Pegli, Italy, 12 June 1888, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Conradi, Willy To Anton Seidl, Chicago, 29 September 1892, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dannreuther, Gustav To Anton Seidl, New York, 27 March 1897, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Derby, Sarah To Anton Seidl, New York, [n.d.], (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - To Antonin Dvorak To Anton Seidl, New York, 29 April 1894, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    [Recommends his friend Kovarich for an engagement.]
  - Dvorak, Antonin To Anton Seidl, New York, 20 November 1892, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dvorak, Antonin To Anton Seidl, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Finck, Henry T. To Anton Seidl, New York, 30 May 1891, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    [Finck, music critic of the Evening Post, asks for Seidl's assistance with Richard Wagner biography and permission to dedicate the book: "Anton Seidl, the greatest of Wagner's interpreters."]
  - Gaertner, Leontine To August Seidl, New York, 2 April 1898, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Gericke, Wilhelm To Auguste Seidl, Vienna, 10 April 1898, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Hols, Julius Staats-Herold Corporation To William J. Guard (Metropolitan Opera House), New York, 23 March 1928, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    [Detailed account of Seidl's death by poison in 1898.]
  - Huberman, Bronislaw To Anton Seidl, [n.p.], 1 January 1897, (1 page a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 33)
    [New Year greetings from the violinist who made his American debut under Seidl the preceding November at age 14.]
  - Joseffy, Rafael To Anton Seidl, Irvington, NJ, 14 August 1890, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 34)
    [Autograph request.]
  - Krolop, Franz To Anton Seidl, Berlin, 28 September 1883, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Lehmann, Lilli To Anton Seidl, St. Louis, 18 June 1888, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Lehmann, Lilli To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 22 March 1891, (8 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 37)
    [Regarding Viennese opera and artists. Lehmann performed the role of Isolde in the first American performance of Wagner's "Tristan and Isolde" on 1 December 1886. With posted envelope.]
  - Lehmann, Marie To Auguste Seidl, Grunewald, 3 April 1898, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 38)
    [With posted envelope.]
  - Levi, Hermann To Anton Seidl, Munich, 13 June 1878, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 39)
    [Levi conducted the first performance of Parsifal on 26 July 1882.]
  - Lindau, Paul To Anton Seidl, [n.p.], 16 November 1882, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Lorenz-Smith, F. To Mrs. Oscar B. Weber, [n.p.], 5 April 1898, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Gilson, Paul To Anton Seidl, Brussels, 23 July 1896, (p.c.s. ) (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Gilson, Paul To Anton Seidl, Brussels, August 1896, (1 p.c.s.) (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Glassenapp, Carl Friedrich To Anton Seidl, Riga, 2 February 1879, (6 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 44)
    [Includes typescript copy and carbons. Glassenapp, Wagner's biographer, requests Seidl to search for material in Vienna relevent to birthday portfolio for Wagner.]
  - Goldmark, Carl To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 27 December 1885, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Grieg, Edvard To Auguste Seidl, Kristiania, Norway, 3 June 1905, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 46)
    [One page damaged. Regarding Seidl's transcriptions of Grieg's Lyrische Stucke.]
  - Gross, Adolf To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 1 June 1897, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Henderson, [William James] To Anton Seidl, New York, 6 Nov 1893, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Henschel, Georg To Anton Seidl, New York, 15 March 1889, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Henschel, Georg To [Anton Seidl], St. Paul, MN, 25 Jan 1898, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 50)
    [First conductor of Boston Symphony Orchestra.]
  - Herrmann, T. To Anton Seidl, St. Gilles, [n.d.], (1 page a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 51)
    [Written on calling card]
  - MacDowell, Edward Alexander and Marian To [Auguste Seidl], New York, 1898, (1 page a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 52)
    [Condolences regarding Seidl's death.]
  - Mancinelli, Luigi To Anton Seidl, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Marteau, Henri To Anton Seidl, New York, 189?, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Marteau, Henri To Anton Seidl, Paris, 20 December 1894, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Mikalovich To Anton Seidl, Budapest, 13 September [n.y.], (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Morrison, Louisa To Anton Seidl, New York, 22 June 1891, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Mottl, Felix To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 1 September 1879, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Mottl, Felix to Anton Seidl, Vienna, 10 Sept 1879, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Mottl, Felix To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 5 October 1879, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Mottl, Felix ToAnton Seidl, Vienna, 22 October 1879, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Mottl, Felix To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 15 November 1879, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Mottl, Felix To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 9 May 1880, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 63)
    [A colleauge of Seidl's in Bayreuth in 1876 and 1897. Translated phrase "...so anxious for your opinion of my opera."]
  - Mottl, Felix To Anton Seidl, Karlsruhe, 23 May 1897, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Navarro, Rafael To Anton Seidl, Brooklyn, 7 March 1897, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Neumann, Angelo To Anton Seidl, Leipzig, 4 January 1882, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 66)
    [Translated phrase: "...Let me express my pleasure...at the brilliant success of 'Tristan and Isolde.'"]
  - Nordica Dome, Lillian to Anton Seidl, London, 12 June 1897, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Olsen, Ole To Anton Seidl, Kristiania, Norway, 20 June 1898, (2 pages a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Patti, Adelina (Nicolini) To Mina, Chicago, 4 March 1889, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Peck, Janet M. To Anton Seidl, Washington D.C., 1 March 1895, (1 telegram) (Box 1, Folder 70)
    [Western Union.]
  - Peck, Janet M. To Auguste Seidl, Munich, 14 April 1897, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Perotti, Julius To Anton Seidl, Budapest, 8 October 1892, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Plancon, Pol To Auguste Seidl, Paris, 5 April 1898, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Powell, Maud To Anton Seidl, Washington D.C., 3 September 1893, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Powell, Maud To Anton Seidl, New York, 26 January 1898, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Powell, Maud To Anton Seidl, New York, 20 February 1898, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Powell, Maud To Anton Seidl, New York, 28 March 1898, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Powell, Maud To Anton Seidl, New York, 29 March 1898, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Reischmann, Theodor To Auguste Seidl, New York, 8 March 1891, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Remenyi, Eduard To Anton Seidl, New York, 9 November 1891, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 80)
    [Note: Written in Hungarian, English, and German. Refers to Seidl as "...one of the world's greatest musical leaders."]
  - Richter, Hans To Anton Seidl, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Richter, Hans Testimonial letter, Vienna, 13 May 1876, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 82)
    [Note: Testimonial on Seidl by his former conducting teacher Hans Richter who recommended him to Wagner.]
  - Richter, Hans To Anton Seidl, London, 1884, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 83)
    [Translation: "...Remember the Master [Wagner] whom we can never repay for what we have to thank for him."]
  - Richter, Hans To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 24 July 1888, (1 p.c.s.) (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Richter, Hans To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 13 November 1889, (1 p.c.s.) (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Rimsky-Korsakoff, Nikolaus Andreus To Anton Seidl, n.p., n.d., (1 calling card) (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Rive-King, Julie To Auguste Seidl, New York, 21 May 1898, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Scaria, Emil To Anton Seidl, Vienna, 17 December 1882, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scharwenka, Xaver To Anton Seidl, New York, 16 December 1892, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scharwenka, Xaver To Auguste Seidl, New York, 29 March 1898, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Seidl, Anton To Ruthardt, Beyreuth, 22 August 1876, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Seidl, Anton Recipient unknown., New York, 1 March 1887, (1 page a.n.s.) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    [Written on verso of calling card. Gift of Harry Mack.]
  - Seidl, Anton To Auguste Seidl, Boston, 2 March 1889, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    [Translation: Note regarding success of "Ring" performances in Boston.]
  - Seidl, Anton To Auguste Seidl, Bayreuth and London, 189- and 1897, (12 telegrams) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    [Reports of successful performances.]
  - Seidl, Anton Open letter, Fleischmann's, 4 May 1894, (7 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Seidl, Anton To [Julius Holz], Del. County, NY, 3 June 1895, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Siloti, A. To Anton Seidl, Antwerp, 19 June 1896, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sinding, Christian To Anton Seidl, Kristiania, Norway, 3 March 1894, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    [With postmarked envelope. Thank you card.]
  - Smareglia, Anton To Anton Seidl, New York, 5 January 1891, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Story, Emma Eames To Auguste Seidl, New York, 23 March 1897, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    [Condolences for Seidl's death.]
  - Story, Emma Eames To Auguste Seidl, Florence, Italy, 1 April 1898, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Sutro, Rose To Auguste Seidl, [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Thomson, Anne To Anton Seidl, Corkerhill, 1 September [n.y.], (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Thomson, Cesar To Anton Seidl, Liege, 22 July 1896, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Urso, Camilla To Auguste Seidl, New York, 30 March 1898, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Vanderbilt, George Washington To Anton Seidl, New York, 17 November 1894, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Wagner, Cosima (wife of Richard Wagner) To [Anton Seidl] "copie", [n.p.], [n.d.], (5 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages a.n.s.) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    [With copy in unknown hand.]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, [n.p.], 10 January 1878, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 23)
    [Translated excerpt: "..we are very much devoted to you and take the liveliest interest in your career..."]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 3 October 1878, (1 page t.l.) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, [n.p.], 3 January 1879, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 16 July 1879, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 31 October 1879, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 28 November 1879, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 26 December 1879, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Naples, Italy, 18 January 1880, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 30)
    [Cpy in unknown hand. Exhibition note: "With instructions from Wagner on the Leipzig performances of Tristan."]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 19 January 1880, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    [With copy in unkown hand and postmarked envelope. ]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 14 January 1881, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Wagner, Cosima to Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 5 July 1881, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 17 March 1881, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 31 May 1886, (7 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 35)
    [With typescript copy and carbon.]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 27 December 1887, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    [With enclosures.]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 2 June 1890, (7 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 10 January 1894, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 38)
    [Exhibition note: "...asks Seidl to coach Nordica so that she will be ready to sing in Bayreuth the next summer."]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 21 May 1894, (5 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    [Exhibitioin note: "...has persuaded Siegfried not to accept an offer to go to America, but wishes he could work with Seidl."]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 25 February 1896, (6 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 7 June 1896, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 23 August 1896, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 42)
    [Exhibition note:"Jean de Reszke and Nordica have told her about Seidl's splendid work."]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 9 March 1897, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 43)
    [Exhibition notice: "All Wahnfried thanks you for your consent [to conduct in Bayreuth next summer]...We will have much to say to each other."]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 10 March 1897, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 28 May 1897, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 8 January 1898, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Wagner, Cosima To Auguste Seidl, Bayreuth, 6 July 1898, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 47)
    [Exhition note: "...I still cannot believe that our friend has left us..." With postmarked envelope.]
  - Wagner, Cosima To Auguste Seidl, Bayreuth, 4 August 1903, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Wagner, Eva (at age 12) To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 3 January 1879, (4 pages a.l.s., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 49)
    [Exhibition note: "Hearty thanks for the pretty picture which you sent me, it pleased me very much.."]
  - Wagner, Eva To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 23 May 1886, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Wagner, Eva and Isolde To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, [n.d.], (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Wagner, Isolde To Anton Seidl, Fantasie, 7 September 1885, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Wagner, Isolde To Anton Seidl, Fantasie, 15 September 1885, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Wagner, Isolde To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 11 October 1885, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 25 September 1878, (1 telegram) (Box 2, Folder 55)
    [Readers must use xerox copies.]
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 1 October 1878, (1 page telegram) (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 4 October 1878, (1 page telegram) (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 2 November 1879, (1 page telegram) (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 4 August 188[n.y.], (1 page telegram) (Box 2, Folder 59)
    [ ]
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 10 June 1881, (1 page telegram) (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 23 August 1881, (1 page telegram) (Box 2, Folder 61)
    [Readers must use xerox copy.]
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Dresden, 11 September 1881, (1 page telegram) (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth and Dresden, 1877-1881, (1 a.l.s., 10 t.l. (transcripts), 8 telegrams) (Box 2, Folder 63)
    [Wagner's recommendation for Seidl. Readers must use xerox copies.]
  - Wagner, Richard unspecified recipient, Bayreuth, 7 Sept 1877, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 64)
    [Facsimile of Wagner's recommendation of Seidl. Reader must use xerox copies]
  - Wagner, Richard To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 1878-1883, (10 t.l. (typescript copies) ) (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Wagner, Siegfried (at age 10) To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, 3 January 1879, (3 pages a.l.s., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 66)
    [Exhibition note: "...I am sorry you are away, for we always had such fun..."]
  - Wagner, Siegfried To Anton Seidl, Bayreuth, January 1887, (4 pages a.l.s., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 67)
    [Exhibition note: "...you are destined for while longer to represent and advance our cause in foreign lands..."]
  - Weingartner, Felix To Anton Seidl, Konigsberg, 31 October 1884, (2 pages a.l.s., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 68)
    [Exhibition note "From Weingartner, Asks Seidl to recommend his Sakuntala to Neuman."]
  - Winkelmann, S. To Anton Seidl, Hamburg, 6 May 1881, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Willner, Franz To Anton Seidl, Koln, 27 March 1891, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Miscellaneous envelopes including those from Cosima Wagner., [v.p.], 1891-1868, (11 envelopes, 1 half envelope (damaged) ) (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Miscellaneous letters and memorabilia, [v.p.], [n.d.], 1882-1943, (13 items, 3 pages photocopies) (Box 2, Folder 72)
    [Includes thank you letter for Seidl's participation in benefit concert for victims of Rhine flood, Berlin 1882; exhibition notes. ]
- Series II: Cataloged Documents and Manuscripts
  - "About Conducting" essay, [n.p.], [n.d.], (16 pages a.m.s., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    [Exhibition note "Original manuscripts of Seidl's two articles on conducting."]
  - Holz, Julius "Aus Anton Seidl's Leben", [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 pages t.m.s.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    [Biographical notes on Anton Seidl.]
  - Lindner, Eugen Essay, "Eine Lohengrin-erinnerrung," Duetche Revue; p. 308-312, Weimar, 28 August 1850?, (5 pages p.m.) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Essay, "About Conducting II.", [n.p.], [n.d.], (20 pages a.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Seidl's rehearsal list of singers and orchestra members for first performances of "Der Ring des Nibelungen.", Bayreuth, 1875, (30 pages bd., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    [On microfilm. With exhibition notes. ]
  - Seidl, Anton Autobiographical notes: "Im Jahr, 1872", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages a.m.s., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 6)